Visual Geometry Group (VGG)
Department of Engineering Science
University of Oxford

⊠ cxzheng@robots.ox.ac.uk

lyndonzheng

Homepage: https://chuanxiaz.com/

# Chuanxia Zheng

### Research Interests

My research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for scene understanding and synthesis. I have done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of *synthesizing a photorealistic virtual world*.

## Education

Nanyang Technological University 2	017.08-2021.06
Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE	
Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning Advisor: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai	
	014.09-2017.03
MA.E. in Automation Science	
Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot	
Beijing Jiaotong University	010.09-2014.07
B.E. in Electronic and Information Engineering	
Employment	
University of Oxford	2022.12-now
PostDoctoral Researcher in Computer Vision	
Research interests: 2D and 3D scene synthesis, and unsupervised learning	
· ·	022.09-2022.11
AI research counselor in computer vision and machine learning group	
Research interests: 2D image generation, completion and translation  Monash University  2	021.08-2022.08
Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology	021.06-2022.06
Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation	
Huawei Research	017.01-2017.06
Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab	
Research interests: face recognition and generation	
	016.05-2016.09
Research Intern at Fundamental Research Center of Tencent Work on news recommendation	
Awards & Honors	
NeurIPS 2022 Scholar/Travel Award	2022
NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award	2022
TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award	2021
NTU Research Scholarship	2017
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing	2014
National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best one in Be	eijing) 2013
Hanergy Scholarship Award ( <b>Top 1</b> %)	2012
Siemens Scholarship Award ( <b>Top 1</b> %)	2011
Press Coverage	

1110 11cws. 1110 Sobil Cubbanding 1 iib Thosis Hward 2022	2022
Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng	2022
kknews, Sohu, NetEase: AgileGAN — a new tool for creating stylized portraits	2021
Research Experience	
VinAI, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Prof. Hung Bui Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression one paper accepted by NeurIPS(1), one paper accepted by ICLR(1)	2021.11-2022.08
<b>Department of Data Science &amp; AI</b> , Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai Research interests: nature scene generation and completion three papers accepted by CVPR(1), ECCV(2), one paper submitted to TPAMI	2021.08-2022.08
Mechanobiology Institue (MBI), NUS, Singapore, Prof. Lim Chwee Teck Cooperator on cell nuclear generation one paper accepted by Plos one(1)	2020.01-2021.10
Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann Research interests: photorealistic image generation seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)	2017.08-2021.06
IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation	2014.09-2017.03
Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(1), NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)	

2022

# Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(1), NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)

NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022

- [18] Minghui Hu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation. In *The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2023.
- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *Thirty-sixth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems* (NeurIPS), 2022.
- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan\*, **Chuanxia Zheng**\*, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (*ECCV*), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision(ICCV)*, pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.

- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, Chuanxia Zheng, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

### Preprints

- [4] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer*.
- [3] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. *Under reviewer*.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer*.
- [1] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *Under reviewer*.

### Academic Services

#### IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence **TPAMI** International Journal of Computer Vision **IJCV** IEEE Transactions on Image Processing TIP IEEE Journal of Automatica Sinica JAS IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021) TMMTCSVT IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology Computer Vision and Image Understanding **CVIU** The Visual Computer TVCJ Neural Computing and Applications **NCAA**

Conference Reviewer	
Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference (CVPR) 2020, 2	021, 2022, 2023
European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	2020, 2022
International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2019, 2021
International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	021, 2022, 2023
The Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2023
Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2022
International Conference on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH)	$2021,\ 2022$
International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	2022
ACM Multimedia (ACMMM)	$2021,\ 2022$
International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)	2023
International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2022
Talks	
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU	
· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	2022.09
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2022.09 2022.08
·	
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2022.08 2022.06
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH	2022.08 2022.06
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, UST	2022.08 2022.06 C 2022.01
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, UST Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2022.08 2022.06 C 2022.01 2019.11
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, UST Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2022.08 2022.06 C 2022.01 2019.11
Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealsitic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, UST Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Teaching	2022.08 2022.06 C 2022.01 2019.11 2018.06